Guide to the Howard M. Spiro Papers
Medical Historical Library, Harvey Cushing / John Hay Whitney Medical Library
Howard M. Spiro Papers
1918-2012
1960-2012
Ms Coll 42
Medical Historical Library, Harvey Cushing / John Hay Whitney Medical Library
3.5
(7 boxes)
Howard Spiro was head of the Gastroenterology Unit or Section of the Department of Internal Medicine at Yale from 1955 until his retirement in 1999. He was co-founder and first Director of the Program for Humanities in Medicine. The collection contains typescripts of Spiro's talks and addresses; typescripts of essays, mostly related to issues in humanities in medicine; a manuscript autobiography; correspondence related to Yale; reprints of Spiros's articles, columns, and book reviews; and ten original medical illustrations related to gastroenterology that Spiro had collected.
Spiro, Howard M. (Howard Marget), 1924-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Boxes 1-5 from the Estate of Howard Spiro, 2012; boxes 6-7 from Howard Spiro, 2008.
Custodial History
Boxes 1-5 papers were in Howard Spiro's office at 40 Temple Street and donated as part of his estate. Boxes 6 and 7 were donated by Howard Spiro in 2008 and added to the collection as a supplement.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Associated Materials
Records of Howard M. Spiro as Director of the Program for Humanities in Medicine, School of Medicine, Yale University (RU 313). Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library, New Haven, CT.
Biographical / Historical
Howard M. Spiro, Yale gastroenterologist and medical humanist, was born in Cambridge, Massachusetts on March 23, 1924. He graduated from Harvard College in 1944, majoring in English, and from Harvard Medical School in 1947. After internship, residency, and further study in Boston, interrupted by military service, Spiro came with his wife Marian to New Haven in 1955, recruited by Paul Beeson, chairman of Internal Medicine. He established the first full-time Gastrointestinal Unit at Yale. In 1965 Spiro established the Yale-Affiliated Gastroenterology Program, through which he and his graduate fellows worked with community hospitals in southeastern Connecticut. Spiro was known for his strong dedication to patients and to teaching, and for his research on the relationship between the mind and the gastrointestinal tract. He was sole author of the first three editions of his textbook, Clinical Gastroenterology (1st ed, 1970), and was founder and editor of J ournal of Clinical Gastroenterology in 1979. In 1983 Spiro was the co-founder with Enid Peschel and first director of the Program of Humanities in Medicine which featured weekly lectures and conversations. Spiro wrote, edited, or co-edited several books under the aegis of Program, among them Doctors, Patients and Placebos (1986), When Doctors Get Sick (1987), Empathy and the Practice of Medicine(1993), Facing Death (1996), and The Power of Hope (1998). Long interested in the history of medicine and an active member of the Beaumont Medical Club, Spiro and Priscilla Waters Norton published a biography of a former medical dean, Dean Winternitz: Yale Medical School's Passionate Humanist, in 2011. Spiro retired from both his academic position and directorship of the Program in Humanities in Medicine in 1999, but remained associated with the Program until his death in Branford on March 11, 2012.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains typescripts of presentations to various audiences; typescripts of essays; correspondence primarily with his residents, but also some on Yale medical politics and from his sabbatical year in London; an incomplete set of reprints, including his medical journal columns on medical humanities for various journals, and his book reviews; reviews of Spiro's books; and photographs of Spiro with colleagues and family. Some folders of essays also include correspondence related to publications, in particular on Spiro's paper on the Nazi-era Pernkopf Atlas and on his biography of Milton Winternitz. There is also material on Spiro's sucessful attempt to end a prize given in West Germany on liver research named after Nazi doctor Hans Eppinger. Most of the talks and essays are on topics in humanities in medicine, and date from the 1960s to 2012. Highlights include speeches in New Haven during the Vietnam War, medical graduation speeches at Yale and elsewhere, and a draft autobiography. The collection also includes ten medical illustrations, some by Yale medical illustrator Armin Hemberger and dating from before Spiro's career, that Spiro collected.
Arrangement
Organized in seven series: 1. Dated typescript lectures and talks. 2. Typescripts and related correspondence by topic. 3. Draft autobiography and miscellaneous. 4. Reprints. 5. Medical illustrations. 6. Supplement: Correspondence and photographs. 7. Supplement: Additional publications and publications about H.M. Spiro.
Aging; Bioethics; Empathy; Gastroenterology; Gastrointestinal diseases; Health services administration; Human experimentation in medicine; Medical care, Cost of; Medical education; Medicine and the humanities; Medicine, Psychosomatic; Medicine -- Study and teaching (Graduate); National socialism -- Moral and ethical aspects; Patients -- Psychology; Physician and patient; Physicians -- Diseases; Physicians -- Psychology; Terminal care; Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Protest movements -- Connecticut; World War, 1939-1945 -- Atrocities; Autobiographies; Correspondence; Drawings (visual works); Essays; Photographs; Speeches (documents); Gastroenterologists; Physicians; Cahow, C. Elton, 1931-1997; Donaldson, Robert M., 1927-; Garland, Joseph, 1893-; Eppinger, Hans, 1879-1946; Hemberger, Armin B., 1896-1974; Kenney, James Duncan, 1929-2007; Mantell, Harvey; McKhann, Charles F.; Nagler, Richard, 1947-; Norton, Priscilla Waters; Pernkopf, Eduard, 1888-1959; Spiro, Howard M. (Howard Marget), 1924-; Thayer, Walter R.; Winternitz, M. C. (Milton C.), 1885-1959; Yesner, Raymond, 1914-; Pernkopf, Eduard, 1888-1959 ( Topographische Anatomie des Menschen: Lehrbuch und Atlas der regionär-stratigraphischen Präparation, 1943-1952); American Gastroenterological Association; Yale University. Department of Internal Medicine; Yale University. Program for Humanities in Medicine
- Dated typescript lectures and talks, 1967-2012; Series I
  Arrangement
  Arranged by date.
  - "Address to Connecticut Society of American Board Internists", 1967 December 14 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Remarks Intended for Delivery at the Dinner in Honor of Dr. Joseph Garland at Mory's", 1968 May 3 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Scope and Contents
    Garland was a Boston pediatrician who served as editor of New England Journal of Medicine.
  - "Talk to St. Vincent's Hospital Staff", 1960s? (Box 1, Folder 3)
    On community hospitals and on federal funding of medicine.
  - Speeches at Yale against the Vietnam War, 1969-1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - "Remarks for Delivery at Harkness Quadrangle", 1969 October 15
    - "Remarks Intended for Delivery at Harkness Quadrangle on April 21, 1972 in Protest Against the Vietnam War", 1972 April 21
    - "Remarks for Delivering at Harkness Dormitory to the Hospital Workers on January 10, 1973", 1973 January 10
  - "Introductory Remarks Intended for Delivery at the Connecticut Chapter of the American Society of Internal Medicine", 1971 February 10 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Remarks Intended for Delivery at the Annual Student Research Banquet -- Emory University, Atlanta, Georgia", 1971 March 23 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Remarks Prepared for Delivery to the AOA Chapter of Downstate Medical School, Brooklyn, New York", 1973 March 19 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Beaumont and Fletcher at Yale: Remarks at the Dinner for the 200th Anniversary of William Beaumont, New Haven", 1985 November 22 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    On the history of the Beaumont Medical Club.
  - "Old Doctors and Old Patients, Presented at the Midwest Bioethics Center, Kansas City, Missouri", 1987 March 27 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    At the "Silver Rights" Conference.
  - "Splicing in the MD-Gene, " address to the graduating class of Yale University School of Medicine, 1987 May 25 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Published in Yale Medicine.
  - "Splicing in the MD-Gene," address to the graduating class of the College of Medicine of the Pennsylvania State University, Hershey, Pennsylvania, 1988 May 15 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "Passion and Promise (A talk at the graduation of the class of 1993,Yale School of Medicine, May 24 1993)", 1993 May 24 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "World Congress Lecture", 1994 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    On gastroenterology, changing technology, and medical ethics.
  - Talk at Williams College, Fall 1994 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Handwritten outline of a talk to an audience that he presumed would include pre-med majors.
  - "C. Elton Cahow", 1997 May 23 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Memorial talk on Cahow, an abdominal surgeon at Yale. See also Box 7, folder 9.
  - "The Rise and Fall of Psychosomatic Concepts in Ulcerative Colitis," International Conference on Psychological Factors and Inflammatory Bowel Diseases, Ulm, Germany, 1999 June 4-5 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "Tolling the Truth", 2003 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Lecture to an unidentified group. Includes PowerPoint slides.
  - "Dinner Talk", 2004 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    On issues in current medicine as compared to 1944 when Spiro began medical school. Includes PowerPoint slides.
  - "50th Anniversary Remarks" on the Gastroenterology Unit at Yale, 2005 April 2 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Talk on gastrointestinal cancer for a memorial lecture for Albert Mendeloff, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Includes introductory remarks and a PowerPoint presentation.
  - "Passion Not Compassion", 2006 April 4 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    "Talk/Essay" for an unidentified meeting. Included are the slides for the accompanying PowerPoint presentation.
  - "A Visceral Viewpoint: Can the Humanities Mend Medicine?" The Elizabethan Club, New Haven, 2008 March 1 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Includes an earlier version dated January 13, 2008.
  - "A Thank-you from Howard Spiro," Program for Humanities in Medicine, 2008 April 26 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - "Can the Humanities Mend Medicine?" The Buffmire Lecture, 2011 September 13-14 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    With PowerPoint slides. The Buffmire Lecture was sponsored by the Flinn Foundation in Arizona and was given in Phoenix and Tucson.
  - Talk at the Koerner Center, Yale University, on Milton Winternitz, 2012 February 13 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Typescripts and related correspondence by topic, 1968-2000s; Series II
  As these typescripts were left unorganized, they were arranged alphabetically by topics selected by the archivist. The topics overlap. Some folders, especially those on the Pernkopf Atlas and Milton Winternitz, contain related correspondence, and others contain Spiro's handwritten notes.
  - Aging, 1980s-2009 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Contains autobiographical material and a copy of prospectus for the Integrated Model of Aging and Geriatric Education (IMAGE) at Yale School of Medicine.
  - Alternative and complementary medicine, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Ancient medicne, 1999 or after (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Two versions titled "Doctors as Gods" on Egyptian and Greek medicine.
  - Anorexia, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Includes a letter from the journal Drug Therapy and an article submitted for publication in a series of columns that Spiro was writing for the journal. See also Box 7, folders 3 and 4.
  - Death and dying, 1990s? (Box 1, Folder 30)
    Spiro co-edited: Howard M. Spiro, Mary G. McCrea Curnen, and Lee Palmer Wandel, eds. Facing Death: Where Culture, Religion, and Medicine Meet (New Haven: Yale University Press, 1996).
  - Doctors and patients -- General, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 31)
    This category overlaps many other categories.
  - Empathy, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 32)
    Spiro published Howard M. Spiro et al, eds., Empathy and the Practice of Medicine (New Haven: Yale University Press, 1993).
  - Gastroenterology, 1980s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Gastroenterology--Diseases and symptoms, 1980s-2000s (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Includes inflammatory bowel disease, irritable bowel syndrome, gallstones, abdominal pain, constipation, peptic ulcer, and duodenal ulcer.
  - Gastroenterology -- Training of specialists, 1970s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Includes the Yale-Affiliated Gastroenterology Program.
  - Informed Consent, 1990s-2000s (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Managed Care, 1990s (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Medical profession and medical education, 1980s-2000s (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Nutrition, 1990s-2000s (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Organization and costs of medical care, 1990s-2000s (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Pernkopf Atlas, 1997 January-1997 May (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Edouard Pernkopf of Vienna was the author of a Nazi-era anatomical atlas, Topographische Anatomie des Menschen (1937-1960), probably based on preparations made from the bodies of Jewish victims of the Nazi regime. Howard Spiro was invited by Karl Holuber, M.D., Chairman of the Institute of the History of Medicine at the University of Vienna, to participate in a symposium on March 3, 1998. The folder includes Spiro's correspondence and publications by others on the Pernkopf Atlas. There is material on other seminars related to the 50th anniversary of the Nazi doctors trials.
  - Pernkopf Atlas, 1997 August-1998 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Includes further correspondence, the abstract, and versions the paper that Spiro presented, "The Silence of Words--Some Thoughts on the Pernkopf Atlas." It was published in Wien Klin. Wochenschr. 110 (1998): 183-184. Also in this folder is Universitat Wien, "Information for the Users of the Pernkopf-Atlas," August 1997. Howard Spiro asked that this statement be inserted into the Yale Medical Library's copies of the atlas.
  - Placebos (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Spiro published: Howard M. Spiro, Doctors, Patients, and Placebos (New Haven: Yale University Press, 1986).
  - Psychosomatic medicine, 1990s-2000s (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Spiro published: Howard Spiro, The Power of Hope: A Doctor's Perspective (New Haven: Yale University Press, 1998).
  - Sick and disabled doctors, 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Spiro co-edited: Harvey Mandell and Howard Spiro, When Doctors Get Sick (New York: Plenum Medical Book Co., 1987). Folders contain correspondence and accounts of physicians who became ill and experienced the medical system as a patient. See also Box 6, folder 7.
  - Sick and disabled doctors: Follow up to When Doctors Get Sick, 1998-2000 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Survey of doctors' illnesses.
  - Sick and disabled doctors, 2000s (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Uncertainty in medicine and science, 1970s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Winternitz, Milton -- Correspondence and notes, 1986-2011 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Spiro co-authored: Priscilla Waters Norton and Howard Spiro, Dean Winternitz: Yale Medical School's Passionate Humanist (New Haven: Program for Humanities in Medicine, Yale University, 2011). The folder includes correspondence, notes, and recollections by others of Winternitz and other medical faculty members.
  - Yale medical politics, 1968-1970s (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Correspondence and presentations. See also Speeches at Yale against the Vietnam War, Box 1, folder 4, and folders on the "Donaldson Report," Box 6, folders 2 and 3.
  - Miscellaneous essays and notes, 1990s-2000s (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Draft autobiography and miscellaneous, 1950-2012; Series III
  - "Intellectual Trajectories" -- Draft autobiography, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - "How to Choose a Physician" -- Draft of a book for laymen, 1960s? (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Seminar: "Doctors, Friends, and Patients"--Correspondence, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence from Drug Therapy on setting up a column by Spiro, 1988 May 3 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    General
    See Box 7, folders 3 and 4.
  - Retirement letter, 1999 June 10 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous reflections, 1990s-2000s (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Short typescripts of reactions to readings and experiences.
  - Material about Howard Spiro, 1972-1999 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Material that Spiro collected about himself including magazine and newspaper articles. See also Box 7, folder 17.
- Reprints, 1950-2012; Series IV
  See Box 7 for additional publications.
  - Reprints, 1950-1959 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Reprints, 1960-1963 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Reprints, 1964-1966 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Reprints, 1967-1969 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Reprints, 1970-1974 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Reprints, 1975-1979 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Reprints, 1980-1989 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Reprints, 1990-1999 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Reprints, 2000-2012 and n.d. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Reprints of column, "Visceral Viewpoints," from New England Journal of Medicine, 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    On topics in Humanities and Medicine.
  - Reprints of column, "The Optimist" from Scientific American: Science and Medicine, 1994-1996 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    This column by Spiro on topics in humanities in medicine appeared in each of six issues per year starting with May/June 1994. Scientific American: Science and Medicine later became Science and Medicine. The journal began in 1994, was published erratically toward the end, and terminated in 2005. Columns from 1994 to 2003 were published as Howard M. Spiro, The Optimist: Meditations on Medicine: Collected Essays, 1994-2003 (Narberth, PA: Science and Medicine, 2004).
  - Reprints of column, "The Optimist" from Science and Medicine, 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Reprints of column, "The Optimist" from Science and Medicine, 1999-2005 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Medical illustrations, 1918-1930; Series V (Box 5)
  Ten original medical illustrations, 36 x 28 cm., related to gastroenterology. Several were by Yale medical illustrator Armin B. Hemberger. These illustrations date from before Spiro came to Yale and appear to have been collected by Spiro.
- Supplement: Correspondence and photographs
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Boxes 6 and 7 contain materials Howard Spiro donated in 2008, and that were re-located after the main part of the collection was cataloged.
  - Dictaphone transcripts of Howard Spiro, while on sabbatical, to Walter Thayer at Yale, 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Spiro was on sabbatical in 1962-1963 in London, mainly at the Postgraduate Medical School. He communicated with the Section on Gastroenterology by means of dictaphone tapes, a new technology, that enabled a sturdy ring of red tape to be mailed. He corresponded mainly with Walter Thayer who transcribed the tapes. The folder contains the transcripts, a few other letters sent by Spiro, and two examples of the tapes and envelope-mailers.
  - Copies of the "Donaldson Report" on the Liver and GI Section, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    The "Donaldson Report" was a typescript evaluation, "Report of the Review of the Liver and GI Section," by a committee of three medical professors at Yale, headed by Robert M. Donaldson. The report upset Spiro who felt he was targeted by it. The folder contains copies of the report and Spiro's notes on reading it.
  - Correspondence concerning the "Donaldson Report", 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - American Gastroenterological Association Mentors: Correspondence and photographs, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Abbot, Frank K., 1959 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Lewinter, Paul, 1957-1961 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Kaunitz, Paul, on doctors as patients, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Mossberg, Sanford M, 1960-1963 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Nagler, Richard, 1957-1963 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Pittman, Fred, 1964-1965 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Poliner, Irvng J., 1955-1962 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Powell, Alan, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Rosof, Bernard M., 1964 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Schimmel, Elihu, 1960-1962 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: Schioppo, Dominic B., 1965 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: Schwartz, Raphael, 1955-1957 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: Sessions, John T., 1965 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: Tesler, Max A., 1959-1981 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: Toffler, Alan, 1959-1963 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1976-2000 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Photographs: Professional (Box 6, Folder 21)
    Some photographs from this collection were moved to the Photograph Collection and have been digitized.
  - Photographs: Personal (Box 6, Folder 22)
    Informal photographs alone, with his wife Marian, and with friends. Some relate to sailing.
- Supplement: Publications by H. M. Spiro and Articles about H. M. Spiro
  - Curriculum Vitae, about 2005 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Column, "The Human Factor" in Gastroenterology & Endoscopy News, 1986-1988 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Column, "Meditations on Medicine," in Drug Therapy, 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Column, "Meditations on Medicine," in Drug Therapy, 1991-1994 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Column, "Visceral Views," in vgastroenterology.com, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Book reviews in Gastroenterology, 1986-1991 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Spiro was book review editor of the journal Gastroenterology from 1986 to 1989 and wrote many reviews himself.
  - Book reviews by Howard Spiro, 1985-2006 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Appreciations and obituaries by Howard Spiro, 1997-2007 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Typescripts of remarks on Raymond Yesner, Charles McKhann, Kenneth Taylor, Marilyn Smith, C. Elton Cahow (short and long versions), and Solomon Schwartz.
  - Reviews of Howard Spiro, The Power of Hope, 1998-1999 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    Howard Spiro, The Power of Hope: A Doctor's Perspective. New Haven: Yale University Press, 1998.
  - Reviews of other books by Howard Spiro, 1993-1994, 200 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    Folder includes many reviews of Howard M. Spiro, Clinical Gastroenterology, 4th ed. New York: McGraw-Hill, 1993 and a review of Doctors Afield, ed. Mary G. McCrea Curnen, Howard Spiro, and Deborah St. James. New Haven: Yale University Press, 1999.
  - Davies Award, American College of Physicians, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    Spiro was awarded the "Nicholas E. Davies Memorial Scholar Award for Scholarly Activities in the Humanities and History of Medicine." The awardee was expected to give a lecture. The folder contains photographs from the event, and a list of previous awardees from 1993 to 2003.
  - Friedenwald Award, American Gastroenterological Association, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    The Julius M. Friedenwald Medal was the most prestigious award given by the Association. The folder contains an article/reprint: "Presentation of the Julius M. Friedenwald Medal to Howard M. Spiro, M.D.," Gastroenterology 118 (2000): 1229-1232, and a letter to Spiro from Herbert Kaufmann.
  - Spiro's protest against the Eppinger Prize, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    Spiro discovered that the prestigious Eppinger Prize given for liver research by the Falk Foundation in West Germany was named after a Nazi physician, Hans Eppinger, who experimented on inmates in concentration camps. In response to Spiro's criticism of the award, the organization decided not to award it in the future. Folder contains newspaper articles and a copy of Spiro's editorial "Eppinger of Vienna: Scientist and Villain," Journal of Clinical Gastroenterology 6 (1984): 493-494.
  - Additional typescripts on Humanities in Medicine (Box 7, Folder 15)
    Related Materials
    See typescripts in Boxes 1-3.
  - Additional presentation: Alumni Talk, Yale University School of Medicine, 1993 March 24 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    See Howard Spiro's presentations in Box 1.
  - Articles about Howard Spiro, 1947, 1986-2005 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    See also Box 3, folder 13,
  - Editorials from G.I. Guide, edited by Howard Spiro, 1987-1991 (Box 7, Folder 6)